Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/aronszanto (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Technical Product Management
Machine Learning
Artificial Intelligence

Languages

Hungarian Spanish

Certifications

Series 3 Certification (National Commodity Futures Examination)

Honors-Awards

National Merit Scholarship Winner Special Distinction Award All-National, All-Eastern, All-State Orchestras, New York Youth Symphony, World Peace Orchestra, World Youth Symphony Orchestra Winner, Lincoln Center National Chamber Music Competition Signifer Honors Society

Publications

How To Rob An Airbnb

A Kernel of Truth: Determining Rumor Veracity on Twitter by Diffusion Pattern Alone

Aron Szanto

Head of Machine Learning Products @ PathAI | AI R&D at Harvard | Chairman, Zerobase Foundation

New York, New York, United States

Summary

Hi! I'm Aron. I'm an Al scientist, engineering leader, and Former Math Person. My happy place: working hard with brilliant people to solve challenging problems that matter - by building world-class teams and technology.

Currently, I head ML Products at PathAI - a team of 300+ spectacular AI researchers, software engineers, biomedical scientists, and pathology experts, all working together to find novel, AI-powered treatments and diagnostics to help people suffering from diseases like cancer. (If that sounds as cool to you as it did to me, come join us- we're hiring!)

In the past, I've led teams at Kensho Technologies, Harvard, the Zerobase Foundation, and MarketFactory, fighting fake news, Covid-19, and terrorism while approaching the speed of light. Ping me to find out more:)

When not thinking about technology, I love playing cello and ultimate frisbee, cooking, political modeling, and slowly but surely approaching the perfect espresso shot.

Technical areas: Machine learning and artificial intelligence, neural networks and deep learning, representation and multimodal learning, computer vision, digital pathology, natural language processing, natural language understanding, weakly supervised learning, entity recognition and entity linking, knowledge base-aided AI, machine learning infrastructure, misinformation detection, network analytics, high-performance computing, big data systems and analytics, distributed and parallel computing, Python (pytorch, Tensorflow, sklearn, pandas, and friends), C++, Deployment

via AWS, Kubernetes, and Docker, economics and finance, mathematics, modeling.

Experience

PathAl

Head of Machine Learning Products 2022 - Present (1 year)

New York, United States

I lead the ML Products department at PathAI: four divisions of 60+ spectacular AI researchers, software engineers, and biomedical computer vision experts. Our mission is to find novel, AI-powered treatments and diagnostics to help people suffering from diseases like cancer. We're hiring!

Kensho Technologies Head of Natural Language Processing 2018 - 2022 (4 years) New York, United States

- Led creation of \$200MM+ portfolio of ML products deployed to hundreds of thousands of expert users
- Managed people and performance strategy for division of 35+ world-class Al scientists, engineers, and product staff
- Directed ML, software, and product development for AI platform processing 1B+ documents
- Delivered key presentations to investors and board of directors amidst \$44B acquisition
- Before acquisition by S&P Global, led technical effort as principal ML research scientist, designing novel techniques in NLU, weakly supervised text classification, and knowledge base-augmented named entity recognition and linking
- Delivered models and software across all aspects of ML development, from research to production at scale
- Launched and directed research efforts for multiple patented or published NLP products

Zerobase Foundation Founder and Chief Executive Officer 2020 - 2021 (1 year)

New York, United States

- Led global staff of 150+ at public health technology nonprofit corporation providing a free, privacy-preserving, universally accessible digital contact tracing platform to help contain Covid-19 in low-resource environments
- Scaled and managed organization across engineering, ML, product, communications/PR, legal, government affairs, recruiting, and last-mile operations functions
- Liaised with senior executive governmental and private sector partners to deploy technology across several countries, protecting tens of thousands of individuals from potential Covid-19 infection
- Established partnerships with top technology research organizations like Harvard, Max Planck, and Amazon to develop a breakthrough machine learning algorithm that powers the Zerobase platform

Harvard University

Associated Researcher, Department of Computer Science 2018 - 2020 (2 years)

Cambridge, Massachusetts, United States

- Directed research as visiting ML scientist on teams investigating misinformation propagation, fake news, and Visual Question Answering.
- Work appears in top ML publications, such as WWW and KDD.

MarketFactory Product Engineering Manager 2015 - 2018 (3 years)

Greater New York City Area

- Led R&D of next-generation market data and economic analysis products at high-growth fintech startup
- Architected 1.2PB database migration, resulting in a 100x speedup, >95% compression, and zero downtime

R.G. Niederhoffer Capital Management Software Engineer 2014 - 2015 (1 year)

Greater New York City Area

- Built sampling framework for high time-density data (C++) and performed graphical and mathematical market data analysis
- Developed high-frequency trading algorithms from mathematical modeling to execution simulation using time series analysis in C++ and SQL Server, resulting in a 45% implied profit over two years

• Implemented automated parallel network security system for 1024 IP addresses using nmap and PBnJ environment, optimized run time from 6 hours to 3 minutes (C++, Linux Script, TCP/IP)

Education

Harvard University
Applied Mathematics, Economics and Computer Science